Hello everyone, we are at DEFCON at the Creator Corner.
First of all, thanks for TikTok for sponsoring the Creator Corner
and to do the background interviews.
Thanks for Hackerone and also for helping organize it
and all the other sponsors as well.
I have amazing guests today.
We have Jason Haddix.
Hello.
And we have Blaklis.
Yeah, hello.
Nice to meet you here.
Can you start with, you can just say,
where are you at your current journey?
Are you focusing on the background team or something else?
Where are you at?
Jason, can you start with you, please?
Yeah, absolutely.
So I do a little bit of everything right now.
So I just started my own company,
which is a red teaming and penetration testing company
after working for other people my whole life.
But it is heavily influenced by my bug bounty journey.
So a lot of techniques and stuff that are more modern
that you see with bug bounty hunters and stuff like that.
So I still do bug bounty hunting on the side
and my company does training as well for bug bounty hunters,
which we did a talk here at DEFCON,
which I released a couple of methods and stuff like that
from the training.
Awesome.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, yeah.
So really, I'm just trying to get my company off the ground
and, you know, in the interim, find some bugs,
make sure that you stay liquid.
Yeah, so.
Do you also do some, like, group hunting?
Do, yeah.
So people who come to the course,
I think we've had about, at this point,
maybe 250 or 300 people come to the course.
We have a private Discord that they get access to
and we hunt together on a program.
So every two months, we choose usually a wide scope program.
So we started with FIS, then we moved to T-Mobile,
and then we moved to BMW.
So yeah, we've been hunting on those,
having really great success.
Yeah, I feel like this also gives you
a really nice perspective into, like,
first, you see a lot of different people hunting,
you know what mistakes they are making.
I hope to really pick your mind
on some of the lessons that you've had.
Yeah, absolutely, yeah.
Yeah.
How about you?
I know that you had amazing time at Ambassador Awards,
being so much ahead of everyone.
Absolutely, I'm pretty proud of that.
Yeah.
Yeah, I have quite the inverse situation of you.
I co-created a company a few years ago
and I decided to stop everything
and get back to BugBunty full-time
because, like, I really value the freedom
that you can get with BugBunty.
So I decided to, like, keep my company
and do BugBunty full-time again.
And yeah, I'm trying to help the community a lot.
So I'm very active on communities,
on Discord and on Twitter also.
So I'm trying to answer every questions
and things like that.
And I'm super active also
in the French community specifically.
We have, like, a quite large community
with maybe something like 700 people.
And I'm also managing
the Ambassador Awards with a little club.
And yeah, we did pretty good at the World Cup.
So yeah, pretty good.
How did the line-up of events go for you?
Pretty good.
For me personally, that was pretty good.
And it was super fun also
because there's a lot of French people.
For the first time, I guess,
we were, like, 700 from France.
So that's definitely, like, a special event.
But yeah, personally, it was pretty good.
I focused on the Epic Games.
And that was super good.
Awesome.
Okay, we have the first question
from Simone from Twitter.
Will bug bounty hunting remain a viable option
as a full-time career?
And is there an equation that tells us
where is the moment to quit and go full-time?
Jason, let me start with you.
Yeah, I don't think bug bounty
is going anywhere, honestly.
I think that it only grows into more things
that it currently isn't into right now.
At least from the conversations I've had
with a lot of the platforms,
they want to get to the point
where you do things other than just hack things, right?
And hack different types of things.
They want to do defensive stuff, right?
Log ingestion templates,
queries, alert templates.
They want to get to the point
where they can host code.
You can do code review.
So I think that the gig economy
for security people grows even more
over the next five or six years,
which brings in new types of people,
which I'm kind of excited about, right?
That's not stuff I do every day.
So it'd be cool to check that out.
And so I think that when that expands,
you have other people who come in
and then you have the platforms
that keep on pushing
and then you have more opportunity.
So I think that going full-time
can become a viable option for a lot of people.
I also know, though, from my conversations
with bug hunters who take my class,
then all the private discords
that exist and stuff like that,
there is a little bit of a backlash right now
of maybe the talent in the industry
is not being treated as well as they used to be
by some of the platforms.
And so a lot of people
are kind of moving to pentest models,
but hosted by companies
who do hybrid bug bounty kind of models, right?
So they're pentest companies,
but you go 1099 work for them like bug bounty.
And so you can get guaranteed money for your time.
It may not be a ton,
but it is enough to sweep by.
So it'd be interesting to see
how the talent wants to evolve their journeys.
Yeah.
Yeah, you said you quit your company
for a full-time bug bounty.
Did you look for a specific equation
as the question set of like,
okay, this many bugs,
this many agents, whatever,
now I can quit?
Or for you it's just...
I mean, I was doing bug bounty for a long time.
It was like a side of my job.
I mean, I knew that it was already profitable.
And I think that's quite important
because when you're doing bug bounty full-time,
you're like relying on like your own rentability
and you need to have some success.
That's quite important
because if you are not sure about that,
that would be a super stressful job
doing bug bounty full-time
with like you're not sure of getting enough money
or something like that.
That can be quite stressful.
And definitely you won't like the job
of doing bug bounty full-time.
If you don't have like a bit of savings,
maybe one or two years of savings
or something like that,
that's definitely maybe not a good idea
to get to full-time bug bounty.
So yeah, I'd say one thing that is important
is having some savings.
And I've tried maybe for a year or something
and see if you're like,
you're getting enough money to just come there.
I'd say that's pretty much important.
Yeah, of course.
Another question from Nate.
It's actually very relevant
because I created the content here yesterday
with Mattel who's 16 years old and has crazy bugs.
And the question says,
many successful bug bounty hunters
started their journey into hacking at a very young age.
Do you think natural talent is essential
for success in bug bounty
or hard work and determination can be enough?
I think hard work and determination can be enough.
I've seen plenty of people
who are older crush bug bounty.
In fact, some of the people
at the million-dollar hacker market are very old.
And then there's more of those million-dollar hacker people.
If you were to count all the platform work
that they do on all the different platforms,
like the million-dollar hacker work
is usually a hacker one thing.
Yeah.
But many people have crossed the million-dollar mark
across all platforms.
And they're in there.
Mark Wichfield is a good example.
He's one of the best at SQL injection in the world
and account takeover bugs and access bugs that I know.
I've met, I've talked to him, I've interviewed him.
And I think he's upwards of 50 or something like that.
So I think it's hard work and determination.
I think it's also one that's not talked about in that
is that also you could start late
and still be successful if you grind.
But also a lot of us have had 20 plus years of pen test
or security work under our belt
and then transition into bug bounty.
So there's a little bit of longevity
and exposure to the world that helps as well.
A lot of people think,
oh, I'm just going to go into bug bounty
without ever having had any pen test experience
or anything.
That's a hard transition
to move into offensive security
purely just to go into bug bounty.
So yeah.
Yeah.
Maybe we won't answer each question for both of you.
I'll ask another question to you.
It's also very relevant to this time
because we had so much good research now.
And the question says,
generally researchers post content of their research
after mass reporting the vulnerability
in bug bounty programs.
It sometimes can be discouraged
of getting duplicates on these bugs.
What is your take on this?
What will you do with the research
that you're so inexperienced?
I agree with that.
I'm definitely posting my research
once I was paid for that
because if I spend a lot of time
researching from something that is quite new,
I'm definitely using that.
I need to be paid for my research,
but that doesn't make it not valuable
because there's a lot of people
that can be impacted by my research
and I will probably focus on
maybe five, six, seven, eight programs.
That doesn't mean that there won't be
anything vulnerable again after that.
But eventually you will need maybe
to do some recon and something like that
to find the targets I missed
or the targets every paper will miss.
That's pretty much the same as everything.
I mean, you'll need to make some research
and get some people that will be vulnerable
and that are quite hard to find.
And for that, you need to maybe
do a better job than others on recon.
So yeah, that's the point, I guess.
Yeah, here's a nice question.
We'll do the roundtrip on this.
From Pavel from Instagram,
what is the best and the worst moment
of your backbouncing career?
Jason, what's the best moment
Best moment of my bugbouncing career,
I think it was when I hit the number one
on the Bug Crowd leaderboard.
So very early on in Bug Crowd's history,
in like the first 10 years of it being around,
I was battling back and forth
with another hunter named Bickwork
to be number one on the leaderboard.
And this was before bugbouncing
was critical mass, right?
So there was maybe, I would say,
5,000 at most active hunters
on the platform at that point.
But it was still a really big deal for me.
And so I won the number one spot
and they did a little party at Defcon
and they gave me a little badge
and stuff like that.
And so that was really special for me
to hit that spot.
I think that was cool.
Yeah, nice.
What is the best moment of your career?
The best moment?
Yes.
That's a good question, to be honest.
I guess that's when I started
to get some very cool bugs.
When I started on Swisscom,
little too late,
I learned the system,
definitely much, much better.
And I did started to get
some very, very, very cool bugs.
And they were like super cool with that.
And they even were like impressed
and that was definitely like
really my first very cool bugs
on Bug Monty.
So yeah, that's a special feeling for that.
Yeah, I guess that's...
What is the worst moment of your career?
I mean, I think it's always
the worst moment when you have
what you know is a really impactful bug.
And like the client just doesn't get it
and you submit it
and they don't understand
and you arbitrate for yourself
and try to get people
on the platform involved.
And it just goes nowhere.
And then you just have to abandon that bug.
And I've had that several times
and it feels really bad.
Like it feels horrible.
And there's just no recourse
at some point, right?
So those are some of my worst moments.
Yeah, I think there's stuff like that.
I mean, there's a lot of lows
in bug bounty and self-doubt,
but for the most part,
it's a good experience
if you're trying and succeeding.
So yeah.
I guess pretty much the same for me.
I mean, like frustration is kicking out sometimes.
Like you try to explain
everything correctly
and like you have the impression
of never being heard sometimes.
That's quite frustrating.
But except from that,
I think at the moment
when I'm on a program
and I decide to switch
to another program,
and I really have the impression
that I will never find
something as critical
as what I already found.
A bit of like the imposter syndrome,
especially when I started,
that was quite hard to just ignore it
and just continue.
That's also something
that I'm trying to discuss
with a lot of the community,
with a lot of people
from the community, excuse me.
I'm trying to like explain
that you should just ignore it.
Just go, just go.
Go hit the wall until it breaks.
One of the things
I talk about in the course
is don't get emotionally
attached to a bug.
I know that people put
a lot of their heart and souls
into finding these things in time,
but you can't
because you just never know
what the outcome is going to be
to move on to the next thing.
Yeah, it is so hard.
I mean, I'm still doing it.
I know that's definitely
not a good idea,
but like you get like five bugs
and you think that it will be like 100k
and you can be like,
oh, come on, just forget about it.
But yeah, we all know
that we should try to avoid that.
But sometimes it's hard.
Do you guys ever like,
you report some good bugs
and then the night
that you report them or whatever,
you're like you have trouble sleeping
and you're like checking to see
like if they triaged them.
And you're like, yeah, definitely.
That happened to me
like one month ago
with some crazy bugs.
I did this with the LAC,
but especially for us in Europe,
I guess you can relate.
But the triage often happens
in the night hours.
Yeah.
So when I have like a really good bug
and I'm really,
I don't really want the response.
You wake up in the night.
I am looking at this email.
To be honest,
I say that I'm trying to like
not be emotionally attached to my bugs,
but I still have like a special inbox
in my mail.
And that's like the only notifications
that can like wake me up during the night.
I'm causing all notifications
except those ones
because I want,
if I get a bounty,
if I see that mail that say
you earned some cash,
it will definitely wake me up.
How do you have it set up?
Like what kind do you use
on the notifications of this?
I'm using like a custom one.
Yeah, I have a custom one
that just put everything
filters
and just throw me some notification
with some nice effect.
If it's on my computer,
I have some nice effect
with like dollars.
It's like the HackerOne leaderboard
when someone scores something.
Yeah, pretty much the same.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And the sound as well.
Oh, this is me, this is me, this is me.
Yeah, I have something,
a free custom.
Very cool.
I learned through this as well.
The worst moment of my career
was during this event
after like one and a half weeks
into the virtual phase.
I had no bugs.
And it was my first event.
And I was like, oh no,
they will never invite me again.
I feel so bad.
The guys are so good.
I knew nothing.
And the best moment of my career
was one week later
when I actually found some bugs.
Ah, there you go.
And then I came here,
I discussed with everyone
and I learned so much.
You know, yeah, yeah.
So like my worst and best
came one week apart.
Yeah, that's definitely a good point
because it happened to me also.
Yeah.
I'm going to a live hacking event
with nothing.
And I was like,
damn, there's a lot of people
finding a lot of things
and I'm not finding anything.
Yeah.
And yeah, that's pretty hard to manage.
But finally, I mean,
we're quite successful.
So sometimes it works,
sometimes it just doesn't.
Yeah, it's just,
you have to keep at it.
Yeah.
It somehow works.
OK, next question from David from Instagram.
Is Backbone VFX progressing harder
but easier as the years go by?
Maybe start with you for a change.
Yeah, for me,
it's like just always the same things.
We need to evolve
with the new techniques
and the new content
and new technologies.
And it's pretty much always the same.
If you do like learning constantly,
that's the point.
It will be quite always the same, I guess.
We saw a lot of more protective things.
There are always some new technologies
to protect things better.
But we also found a lot of new techniques.
And if you just stay constantly
at a good technical level,
I think it's quite like always the same thing,
always the same level.
I think it's hard.
I don't want to lie to people, right?
Like bug bounty is hard.
It is much harder
than what a lot of people come out
ready to experience.
So like I remember the transition
from pen testing web apps full time as a job
and then trying to do bug bounty
and realizing like,
oh, like a lot of the bugs
that you find in pen tests
are either not payable
or you have to chain them
so you get like way more impact.
And then some of the bug classes
are just not available on customers
who have had a running bug bounty for a long time
because they've already been remediated
all that like kind of medium hanging fruit or whatever.
And so it is harder.
And so like if you expect to come out of,
you know, like doing like a SANS course
or like, you know, having like your CEH
or something like that
or some kind of training
and just like kill it at bug bounties,
it is a little bit of a rough awakening.
It is much harder than that skill level.
But once you put time into it,
and I sincerely believe this,
success in bug bounty
is based on the time invested.
Like once you become an expert
of any of the applications or technologies
that that program is asking you to look at,
once you become like a power user of their app,
like there are places
where no other bug hunters will have tested.
Eventually you'll find that
and you'll find bugs
and you'll find success,
but it takes a lot of time.
Yeah, I can 100% relate to this.
I was a bandit and I was like,
yeah, I know a lot of vulnerability classes.
I'm studying bug bounty reports.
I'm reading write-ups
and I kind of know what they are finding also.
Will it be easy?
And then I was like,
hmm, it is not as easy as I thought.
Also I had to at the same time,
like creating channels and stuff,
like I had to learn all the business sides too.
I was like, yeah, I can do,
I can do both at the same time, not a problem.
It turns out not so easy.
So I had to like just focus more on bug bounties.
Now it makes it work,
but I was truly not expecting it to work.
Bug bounty is definitely hard.
The only point is people think
that there's like a lot of other people
that are killing it,
but we are, in fact,
we are not so much people
that are really successful in bug bounty
and that's not from the things
that's because it's definitely hard.
You also have the social media effect too, right?
Oh yeah.
Like you think that there's,
on any given open program
that's open to the internet,
that's public,
you think that there's,
you know, thousands of people looking at it.
I've been on the back end
of a bug bounty platform
and at any given moment,
it's not thousands,
it's more like, you know,
50 or 60 at a time.
So there is still opportunity there,
but what you see on social media
is everybody's saying,
oh, I succeeded at this program.
I've got 20K.
And then you'll like get discouraged.
You'll be like,
I'm not even gonna hunt on that program.
It's probably already taken care of.
And it's like,
that's actually not the truth most of the time.
So yeah.
Yeah, I have a question
saying pretty much this.
I, from Jacob, I'll give you the email.
I approached bug bounty a few times.
Usually after two or three evenings,
after two or three hours,
I'd give up after finding anything.
And at the same time,
I see other people finding bugs on this target.
How should I deal with this?
For me, it's great to see.
And to be honest,
I saw that a lot.
I had some brilliant colleagues
from pen testing and things like that.
They were like super technically good
and they were like doing the bug bounty
and they failed completely.
The reason is if you spend like hours
or just a few days,
yeah, sure, you won't feed anything.
I mean, generally I can spend
like years on the target.
So yeah, definitely with people
that are like spending months,
years on the target,
yeah, for sure you won't find anything
in a couple of days.
You need to like build some knowledge.
You're like attacking some mature programs.
If a program have a bug bounty program,
they're definitely like aware
of like the common pitfalls
and things like that.
So yeah, definitely you will need
to like get some knowledge about the app.
So you will need like weeks,
at least weeks, months, maybe years
to get efficient for a bug bounty program.
So yeah, if you just take a few days
and then you just give up.
Yeah, definitely.
That's not a good strategy for me.
Yeah.
I think that there's some,
well, I mean, that is definitely true
what he's saying in the email, right?
It's like you can put a couple hours into it.
It depends on the type of application, right?
So like if there's not a lot
of functionality to an app
and you look at it for two or three hours
and you've gone through
common content discovery,
you've looked at all the JavaScript
and analyzed all the routes,
there's no bypasses to anything,
there's no injection,
they're using up-to-date everything, right?
Well, then that's kind of it, right?
And you can move on.
But for big applications
that serve multiple customers,
have tenants that are SaaS programs
or something like SaaS products,
yeah, you need to spend weeks
to understand the product.
And then there's some shortcuts, right?
Like, so like one of the things
we talk about is like,
and other big web hunters do
to find success is like
there are functions of an application
that are usually paid, right?
And you can pay money
to get access to features
that probably nobody else has tested
if you're willing to invest
something up front, right?
So this is a big, you know,
Zshano move, this is a big,
I mean, like a lot of the big hunters
will pay for access
to the premium tier of the product
that has extra features.
And those extra features
have never been tested before.
So you can find quick success
sometimes on those features.
But yeah, I mean,
like the deeper you get
in the application,
the more success
you're going to have usually.
And so, yeah.
Laftis, how do you deal with JS files?
What tooling do you use
to analyze them?
And especially like
modern single-grade applications
with a lot of applications
to help change, right?
I mean, I'm quite a monkey for that.
I mean, I'm still doing
everything by hand.
I'm just like getting the source code
and just using some online tools
to beautify everything
and just reading it.
But I'm friends with Kevin Mizu,
so I will start to use.
Yeah, yeah, I will start to use it.
So definitely I will try
to play a bit smarter
because yeah,
I'm doing everything by hand.
The only tool I'm using right now
is just BEP and a browser.
So that's pretty much for me.
Yeah, I'd like to...
I mean, I got an answer for that one.
Sorry, I know we're trying
to bounce back and forth.
So in the class,
I wasn't very good
at JavaScript analysis
and I wanted to offer my students
a really great module
on analyzing JavaScript.
So we did like a tiered approach
and I dove into it
for like three months
and researched it.
So, you know,
for unobfuscated JavaScript, right?
With something that's not packed,
that's not, you know,
chunked and stuff like that
or is just raw JavaScript,
like JS Loose is my favorite tool
right now and the BURP extension
that instruments JS Loose
across JS files is fantastic.
It'll automatically pull out the routes,
all parameters assigned to those routes,
what the requests look like.
It pulls out a bunch of data for that.
So JS is really good
on unobfuscated JavaScript.
For obfuscated JavaScript,
a lot of us are switching to JS Weasel,
which is a paid tool.
But it is super fantastic
because it does automatically,
it does automatically
like apply source map files
if there's stuff to get it back
to raw JavaScript.
It also creates that sidebar
that usually you'd have to control F
to like find all these references
to like, you know, routes,
other protocols being called,
you know, post messages,
all this stuff.
It's all on the sidebar broken down for you
and you just click on a JavaScript file
and it's like, here's everything.
And so I really, I really like JS Weasel.
And then it also has,
I don't know what Charlie does,
but it also has tech in it
to load all of the lazy loaded JavaScript files
once it finds a source directory
from where they're all,
you know, being loaded from.
So I don't have to worry
about missing functionality in an app
because a lazy loaded function
didn't get loaded in the app
because I missed it, right?
It finds it for me
and then puts it into the analysis tree
on the right.
So I like JS Weasel.
Yeah, I want to shout out to Jay.
He let me try that pool
for the live hacking event
and it is really nice.
It was great for us, yeah.
The bug I duped you on, on Epic Games,
I actually found it when I,
also thanks to this,
because I could,
I had just the routes of this application
in the JavaScript
and I just copied this to Intruder.
That's how I like noticed
the important part of this, of this chain.
So it's like, it saves a lot of time.
So now, yeah.
Yeah, thanks, thanks Charlie
for letting me try that too.
Yeah, Jason, I'd like to pick your mind
a little bit on the people
you see starting the bug bounty career.
If you, the question says,
if you start bug bounty today,
what would you do differently?
But like, I'd like to respond based
on the people that start today
that you observe.
I think it goes back to the last question.
I think learn JavaScript early, right?
Like modern web applications,
these days are,
a lot of them are front-end
JavaScript frameworks
and then back-end APIs.
So API hacking and JavaScript
were, would be technologies
that I would, or I guess like
types of hacking
and types of technologies
I would learn earlier
in my career, I think.
But the other function is just,
I find a lot of bug hunters
get really enamored
with the idea of recon.
And I'm a recon guy, right?
So they'll find,
they'll like get into recon
and automation and scanning,
but they won't move past
those skillsets very often.
And like, you have to realize,
and I talked about this
on Critical Thinking's podcast.
It's like the recon is only
to find you more targets
to actually hack.
The web hacking is the core skillset.
Now I have a lot of success
in finding shit that people leave online
that they shouldn't, right?
Because I'm really good at recon.
Yeah, I guess.
I have so many notes from you,
from you talking,
just a 90 minute talk.
Wow, I'll spend all day
running these tools.
When do I hack?
Yeah, exactly, right?
And so, at the end of the day,
you get these hunters that are,
I do all this recon and scanning
and then they're disappointed
after they've done all this work
and it doesn't yield any payouts, right?
Because it's just,
it's like at the end of the day,
you have to go hack the website,
which is a whole domain
of website hacking
or some kind of technology hacking.
And so, even if you're following me,
understand I do the recon
first of all, because I love it.
I'm in love with finding
like stuff that gets left out
on the internet.
And second of all, I do it
to get an advantage to hack, right?
It's not do it just to do it.
So, I find a lot of people get
stalled in that trap, I think.
Yeah, I certainly have as well.
When I tried like a lot of recon,
I expected the recon
to just give me back all the stuff.
Yeah, and it doesn't.
I expected just the SQL injection,
the search, the read.
Oh no, come on.
Why does it not work?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The next question from Gautam,
I will answer this,
because I don't know
if you can add anything.
Is the digital nomad lifestyle
the ideal lifestyle
for a background hunter?
And it is ideal,
but you have to balance it out.
Because the thing is,
if you're living in
whatever your basis is,
like 100% productivity,
you have to accept that
when you travel,
you will not be at your 100%.
You will not have your environment.
You often do not have
the external screen,
your desk, your chair, whatever.
Also, if you're traveling
and you want to be somewhere
for a while,
you will naturally do more things
on the computer,
which also affects this.
So for me,
I do at the moment
travel for winter,
but not for the whole year,
because I have to balance that.
When do I want to focus
on backbouncing?
I want to also do backbouncing,
but I know that when I travel,
it will be a little less.
So it can be ideal,
but obviously,
with the flexibility of backbouncing,
you can be anywhere,
anytime, you have no meetings.
So it's hard to find a job
that's better suited
for the digital nomad lifestyle.
But you have to accept it.
If you do it a lot,
you have to balance it out,
like how much do you work
and things like this.
For me at the moment,
the priority is getting better
at backbouncing.
And being in Argentina
for three months is super fun.
But if I want to be laser focused,
I'm better off just being at my home
and not doing this.
So it is a hard balance, it's fine.
I'm useless without my home machine.
I have like six monitors,
and I know that's egregious, right?
But if I don't have at least two monitors,
one monitor that's primary burp
and one monitor that's the application,
I'm kind of useless.
I went to the Apple,
because in Poland,
we don't have the Apple Visual Project
to test it,
because there's no Polish language
in Syria and stuff like this.
So I used my opportunity here to see it.
And my main use case is not,
they were showing me like,
they were showing videos,
different photos and stuff like that.
Actually, what I'm interested in
is to have the external screen
with my mouse when I travel.
And there wasn't much about it in the demo,
but it would be cool if there is.
I mean, that's a difficult point
in my working event,
that you just have your laptop
with one screen.
And definitely, it makes the productivity
that's definitely a bit harder
than being at home
with my setup and everything.
I love that HackerOne, though,
has done it at that esports arena
the last three years.
And they have monitors there.
If you get there early and get a seat,
you can get an extra monitor.
That's the goal.
You need to get that early.
So, it's definitely quite hard in Vegas, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
To be honest, I was surprised
because in the life I go there,
I barely saw anyone using
these external screens.
Oh, when I walked in on the second day,
at least in the front part,
I saw a ton of people
using the external screens.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
People were sitting at the desk.
It makes sense to use the screen.
There was no HDMI cable.
I had one, but a lot of people didn't.
Yeah, that explains.
That was the reason, I guess.
Yeah.
Okay, Jason, question to you.
From DDRD, the future.
Backbounty Driven is inconsistent.
How to switch from Backbounty
to Rectum or Penetration Testing
and how to find clients?
Yeah.
So, I'm relatively lucky
because I've spent the better part
of my 20-year career in offensive security
speaking and doing research
and doing public talks
and building a brand.
And that's not a lot of people.
A lot of people don't like to do that, right?
It's a lot of extra work.
It's a lot of writing.
It's a lot of being on camera,
answering questions, research time.
And so, when I built the course,
luckily, I had that brand
and people came to it.
And then, word of mouth from the course
got around saying it was good, you know?
And then, people started coming to me for work.
They were like, hey, I took your class
or I heard someone took your class.
It was really awesome.
We want you to do our pen test, our red team.
We want to consult with you
on like X, Y, and Z and stuff like that.
So, it's really word of mouth referral
for a lot of my work at my new consultancy.
But, I mean, if you cut your teeth on Bugbounty,
you'll certainly be able to do
like most modern web app pen tests.
So, the skill set, you know, graduation
is actually not that hard.
But, you know, other than that,
I think that I'm a big believer
that if you go out and put good things
into the world, good things will come back to you.
And so, you know, I go to a lot of conferences
and speak on my experiences.
I give away most of my methodology
for free in talks a lot of times
or in webinars or whatever.
And I think that that goodwill comes back to me
when, you know, someone who's much younger than me
has gone through some of that content.
They're like, oh yeah, I saw your stuff.
And then, this year, we're looking at doing a pen test.
Why don't you come do our pen test, you know?
And it's like, I know that's not
the traditional sales cycle,
but that's just how it works for me.
Yeah, yeah.
I have a question to you from AMR on Twitter.
Have you ever encountered a bag
that you knew existed and just couldn't exploit it?
Of course, I mean, that was...
That's quite a goal.
I have a lot of bags that I was sure
it wasn't exploitable at all,
but then I'm spending a lot of time on them.
I have a very good example.
I had a very small bag on an app,
and I decided that maybe it was better,
and I decided to spend a few months on it.
And finally, I...
A few months on one bag?
Yeah.
Finally, I did get remote code execution,
and it was paid like 75k.
But that would have been possible,
that it was just nothing.
So you always take the risk.
But yeah, I mean, there's a lot of things
that I never was able to exploit.
And I even tried to share with some people
that maybe I have a different skill set.
That's also one of the strengths of the bag bounty,
is you can share with people.
We can try to collaborate.
But sometimes it's just some dead end.
So that happens.
That happens a lot.
And yeah, that happens.
Definitely, definitely.
I had one on a program where I was testing on it,
and I found an asset,
and I found SQL injection.
And I went as far as to pull the table names
and some like just cursory data out of the database.
But at this company, they were very big.
And so the people who ran the bug bounty
were different than...
It was a different team than the team who did
kind of like patching of servers.
And so the team that...
I submitted the report,
and I conclude all the information.
The team that was the defensive team,
whether it was DevSecOps or whatever,
they fixed the bug because they saw the traffic.
And they fixed the SQL injection.
And then the triage team after that came in
and was like, oh, we can't reproduce your bug.
And I'm like, no, no, no, no.
So I go back to look and it's fixed.
And I'm like, oh, you guys must have fixed it.
And they're like, we didn't do anything.
The triages were like, we didn't do anything.
And so I spent weeks talking with them.
I have table names of your database.
And they're like, yeah, there's no bug.
We're not paying you.
And so it was like super frustrating.
And that was one I still remember to this day.
I tried to arbitrate and just nothing happened.
And I was like...
Nothing happened.
That's part of the triage frustration from someone
because the triage can always have a small discussion
with the developers and try to get the information
on how it was found.
But not every companies are doing that.
That's unfortunate.
But it happens.
And it's like super frustrating.
It happens also to me.
So yeah, that can be very frustrating.
They recently started utilizing Justin Gardner's advice
about recording the BMO, even for like simple bugs.
One of the advantages is this, that if they fix the bug
and it stops existing for some time,
like you have the proof there inside,
where it's harder to get into the situation.
Sometimes you will not be able to get in there.
I mean, like nowadays there's a whole bunch
of free or really cheap screen recording apps
like Loom and stuff like that.
And you can just like do a quick video
of like, here's the bug.
Let me show you how to execute and be done.
And that's it.
I also did the voiceover often.
And then I told them like,
oh, here's the Victim's browser.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's like, I think it's nice.
Yeah, but I mean, sometimes even that's not enough.
Because I mean, they just can't reproduce it.
And even if they have a video, they're like,
yeah, okay, but it doesn't work there.
So, yeah.
Yeah, I mean, it's not, it's not.
It's not better proof.
But it, yeah, yeah, definitely.
What do you think about the future
of the bug bounty space,
considering AI and the web-free industries?
Yeah, so I did a talk last night
called The Dark Side of Bug Bounty.
And one of my slides was about
how platforms are utilizing researcher attack data
and training AI models with it
to build their own vulnerability scanners
and threat feeds that are going to go out
as products to their customers.
And I think without paying the bug bounty hunters
for that research, I think it's very unethical
to train on our data and our research
and then just give it away.
I think that a model like something like Detectify
has when you build a vulnerability check for them.
And then anytime they find it using their scanner,
you get a kickback.
I think that model is way more fair.
But to just take it and run
and start using it in different things,
I think is pretty unethical.
I agree with that.
For me, AI is just a tool.
I don't think that will,
that will probably change
the way we are doing things, maybe.
I'm not sure that will change the industry per se.
That will just be another tool in like a tool set.
But I'm not sure that will change
deeply how things are done
and how the bug bounty industry will evolve.
I mean, the next step for bug bounty
is to target small companies
and trying to get just bigger and bigger.
That's quite a young industry.
It has become maybe like 12 years ago, I guess.
That's still a small industry
and it just can't become bigger.
When Jason started hunting,
that's the bug bounty was created, wasn't it?
Yep.
And yeah, so I don't think that will change anything.
That will just be another tool
and there will be some other tools also later.
And yeah, for me, that won't change anything.
I think there's a lot of power right now
with the current LLMs that exist
to supercharge small portions of what we do.
Like I use AI bots to build bypasses
to very brittle regex checks
for things like SQL injection,
cross-site scripting, stuff like that.
I use them to discover one-day vulnerabilities
in the same vein, right?
If some CVE has been published
and that has an attack string.
Like I know from my 20 years of experience
that these are usually the ways to bypass
very brittle regex filters for web applications.
And so I know I put those into a bot
and then the bot gives me a list of attack strings
based on the CVE to try to bypass
the original protection that they patch.
So I'm using it in like small,
little bite-sized things like that.
I did a talk at Venn's Nahomcon
on some of the stuff I do with it.
What is the most complex you've discovered?
The most what?
The most complex.
The most complex bug?
Yes.
Good question.
I guess you have a lot of complex bugs.
Yeah.
Yeah, I have a lot of super complex bugs.
I'd say in BagMonte it was
the bug I spent like one month on it
trying to get a chain.
I guess that's my most complex code.
It did go from blind SSRF to SSTI,
five writes, two zero days involved in the thing
and finally RCE.
So yeah, definitely my most complex chain.
And it was like maybe one month
searching for it for eight hours a day
for like one month.
Definitely my most complex chain.
Yeah, what did you do with the blind SSRF?
Did you like find some internal domains?
I found that in fact the blind SSRF
was like some PDF, HTML2 PDF
conversion.
So I saw that finally it was like
a sort of blind SSRF inside the renderer.
And finally I was able to just
take the context of the URL
load some HTML file
and it was like a specific PHP library
that was like doing the conversion.
So I found zero days on it
and it was also using some other libraries.
So I also found some zero days on it.
And yeah, it was quite complex to be honest.
And I was super proud
when I did get RCE after like a month.
And the program was also super cool
because it just told me,
yeah, just go for it to search.
For now that's like not super important
but if you think that you can get something better
just do it.
And the flow was there for like an entire month
because I'm pretty sure they were like,
okay, he said that maybe there is something more complex
than something like more impactful
but they were like not super.
I'm not sure that they thought
that I was able to get RCE at some point.
I'm pretty sure they thought that won't happen
but it definitely happened.
So yeah, definitely my most complex thing.
Yeah, nice, well done.
I think mine were at a live hacking event
and I had the opportunity to work
with Shubs and Shanyo on a team.
And I didn't do much on this team, honestly.
Like my specialty was actually the post exploitation
and just like I actually found the documentation
for the code we were looking at
but basically there was a Java app
for the hospitality industry.
And it basically managed everything that had to do
with kind of certain hotels,
doing check-ins, doing checkouts,
handling credit cards, all this stuff.
And a Shub's special is to go out in Docker Hub
and find and see if any of these applications
have been installed in a Dockerized container,
pull it down and then turn a black box test
into a source code audit.
And so we spent I think three weeks
tearing apart this Java app.
And we got a CVE, we got like three CVEs for it.
We found somewhere along the lines of 42 RCE
in this app of different types of XML injection,
XML entity injection, SQL injection,
login bypass, all kinds of stuff.
And then we used those bugs to pivot
onto the internal of the network of the client
and we could pretty much had full access to the client.
So that was one of the funnest experiences.
Again, I only played a small part in that.
Shub's was the mastermind behind a lot of it.
So, yeah.
Well, yeah, probably you're doubting a little bit.
Yeah, probably.
How do you maximize the knowledge you just learn?
Do you just try to look for the specific reliability
in a bunch of programs?
Do you maybe create some offline labs to introduce the bug?
What do you tell me if you see a bug?
To be honest, I'm creating a lot of internal labs
for myself to test for things.
But once I get the knowledge,
I'm just going on some regular programs.
If I have some more knowledge, I will just test more things.
But that won't change how I test the apps.
I get some more knowledge,
so I'm testing just a bit more things.
But yeah, for me, it doesn't change a lot of my methodology.
But yeah, I have a lot of testing labs,
testing environments locally to test some new patterns
and some new things.
Yeah, yeah, that's a good point.
How much time does it usually take
to create a test lab for a particular bug test?
It really depends on what exactly.
But I think my bigger labs are maybe two days of work
to set up everything for some complex target
or complex system.
It can take up to maybe two days, something like that, yeah.
Nice.
How about you?
I think I spend just as much time researching
as I do hacking a lot of the time.
We talked about it in my talk here at the Bug Bounty Village,
but I am constantly, like you, collecting write-ups,
parsing them for what was the attack string?
What do I think the hacker mindset was?
How did they find the function?
Where was it in the application?
What kind of impact did they have to prove with the bug?
And I'm keeping it in notes or keeping it in my head,
but mostly in notes.
And then when I have 50 of those on a new bug class or something,
I try to create a small methodology for myself to replicate.
So yeah, like comprehensive notes, comprehensive research.
It's not just bug bounty reports that I parse.
I parse CVE details a lot.
I parse blogs.
I have a whole feed leaf full of researchers who I respect
who they do a lot of hunting and they blog about it.
And yeah, I'll try to turn it into a step-by-step methodology for myself.
So yeah.
Okay, last question, and we'll have it at the end.
How do you deal with procrastination or nerve melt?
And do you always have high levels of motivation with hunting?
The laugh says it all.
Yeah, no, I don't.
I mean, it's a real big problem.
It doesn't matter what you're doing, honestly.
If you're a pen tester or whatever, or you're a bug bounty hunter.
I think a lot of us have different sort of neurodivergence a little bit.
I know a lot of testers with ADHD.
I know a lot of testers who are on the autism spectrum.
I know a lot of testers who just like, they're just procrastinators, right?
And it's really hard.
I think that I have a cascading set of alarms that helps me be productive.
And then I didn't learn I had ADHD until I was 38.
And so I was very late diagnosed.
And now that I'm medicated a little bit, I can focus a little bit more on work during the day.
But there's no easy answer.
On the burnout phase too, it's like impossible.
I'm sure you guys know, when you're on a roll, you don't want to stop.
It doesn't matter what time it is, right?
It doesn't matter if it's 3 a.m.
If you're in the zone, you don't want to stop.
And so if you're in the zone for a week and you're attacking this program,
you can burn yourself out really easily.
And then that burnout stacks with the triage issues that sometimes you have and stuff like that.
Like we have this saying in the Discord that bug bounty is a scam.
We just talk about it all the time.
We're like, bug bounty is a scam.
Because we just put all this effort into it and then just get a wreck or triage or something like that.
And we get real angry.
And we're like, it's a scam.
We're not doing it anymore.
Shut it all down.
And then, of course, we feel better.
Of course.
Of course, you get a good bounty and you're like, oh, bug bounty is the best.
Yeah, this is great.
Bug bounty, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Free money.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, to me, that's really a good question.
Because at the start, I told you that bug bounty is giving you a lot of freedom.
And that's also the freedom of procrastinating.
And for me, it's quite important.
I accepted that I will procrastinate at some time.
That's something you need to accept.
Because I like to value my mental health.
And that's part of it.
If I don't want to hack, I'm not hacking.
That's why you also need to have a bit of money, to have a bit of savings.
Because sometimes, if you rely only on yourself, that can be quite stressful.
Because you want to procrastinate, but you will force yourself to just work because you
need some money.
And because of that, you will definitely go to the burnout very fast.
The bug bounty is something that is quite complex.
We have a lot of burnout and things like that.
Lack of physical exercise, that doesn't help.
And yeah, I guess it should be okay to just procrastinate.
I'm a big video game fan.
And sometimes, I even spend months on video games.
What do you play?
A lot of things.
Right now, it's Elden Ring.
Oh, such a good game.
Yeah, yeah, definitely.
Definitely.
For example, this year, I decided that from January to May, I decided to just not work
on bug bounty.
I just didn't want to.
I tried to build my French community a bit and things like that.
And I decided to just play video games, take care of myself, do a bit of sports.
And yeah, I mean, that's okay.
But you need to have enough savings or things like that to accept the fact that
sometimes, you're just not working.
And that's definitely okay.
That's part of getting some freedom from bug bounty.
That's the good point for me from bug bounty, is getting the freedom to do whatever I want.
And when I was Pentester, there's no way you can just say, okay, I'm not working.
No, no, no.
You're paid to work, so you just do your work.
Yeah, that's a very good point of bug bounty for me, is being able to accept that I would
just procrastinate and I'm just doing it.
I'm not feeling guilty about that.
I think I get the best of both worlds now, owning my own company, because I can say when
and I don't work, right?
But I can still do that Pentesting work.
I feel like I've taken a couple of two or three weeks stints off for different things.
But the gaming thing and taking time off, I mean, that's kudos to you, man.
Knowing yourself, knowing when you see those signs of stress and burnout is really important.
Yeah.
After five months of gaming, jumping to the Ambassador Rewards company, absolutely killed.
Yeah, definitely.
Yeah, awesome.
Thank you so much for awesome interviews.
Guys, what are you looking forward to I see the rest of 20 years for?
I mean, I'm looking forward to more classes.
I really enjoy building the trainings.
So we have more trainings coming out, not specifically for bug bounty hunters, but for
red teamers and security leaders, too.
So I've done a small stint as a CISO and I have very strong feelings about what a modern
security leadership position should look like.
So I'm going to build some classes around those things and I'm really excited to see
where those go.
Yeah.
For me, it's great, isn't it?
I mean, I will continue to help the community and we'll win the World Cup, obviously.
So yeah.
Hopefully second place behind Pro League.
Maybe, maybe.
I try to not brag too much because generally that can be bad for me.
But yeah, I'm pretty, pretty sure that we'll do, at least we'll do some good, good plays,
I guess.
So yeah, I focus on that, doing some bug bounty.
I just started to get back to bug bounty like a couple of months ago.
So yeah, the objective is to get some good bounties for this year.
So yeah, it's a goal.
Yeah.
Thank you guys so much.
Thank you.
Thank you for having us.
Thanks a lot.